hello everyone this is Frank defreitis
and welcome to holotalk for the week of
January 25th 1999.
a rather short show this week as I've
been in the lab with laser pointer
holography testing in the evenings and
it's been a great deal of time this week
looking to see how far back laser
pointer holography goes
my curiosity was peaked going through
two books number one practical
holography by Graham Saxby
and the other book being homemade
Holograms by John yavini
in saxby's Practical holography he
States on page 38. if the astigmatism of
this beam is corrected by needs of
Optics a spatially coherent being can be
obtained and this has been used
experimentally for making Holograms
though so far not to any extent outside
of the Soviet Union which of course is
now Russia
amazingly enough the papers listed in
the reference at the end of the chapter
are from 1974
1976 and 1980. all of them are from
Russia
if you'd like more information on the
paper send me an email and I'll send you
the authors titles descriptions and
publications
in homemade Holograms page 166 we find
the following
there's currently and this is 1990 one
company in the United States that claims
to produce a laser diode suitable for
holography
Hollow Spectra
Holo Specter uses a diode manufactured
by the Japanese company Toshiba in their
hsd4 laser diode assembly
the wavelength is 670 nanometers power
output is 3.4 milliwatts and the cost is
575 dollars as of January 1990.
the coherency length of the diode isn't
known but has been used by a few
American holographers to produce
Holograms
so I called Bill Arkin and Hollow
Spectra this week and he did confirm the
information he couldn't recall offhand
who the holographers were but did
mention TJ Lake Forest as one person who
was experimenting with diode holography
I went through all of my back issues of
holosphere from the mid-1980s to the
time that they ceased publication and
could not find any information although
the issues may have been too early I
also checked wave front whole Graphics
International but didn't find anything
there either
this week I'll try to go through my
copies of holography news and see if any
company released a report on working
with diodes
I was contacted by a gentleman last week
and said he was making Holograms using a
680 nanometer pointer many years ago but
the results were less than satisfactory
so there has to be news and a history
out there if you have worked with diodes
to create Holograms or know of someone
who was within the last 10 years
please contact me so we can get a nice
background of information together on
this
uh the Holograms that I have created
which you see on my website under the
laser pointer holography link
using the 7.99 laser pointer will be
unveiled to the public for the first
time on Saturday evening March 6th at
the central New Jersey Mensa conference
held at the Holiday Inn at tinican Falls
New Jersey
I will be the keynote speaker for the
event so if you're in the area come out
and be one of the first people to see
these images
I'll have a web page on the event within
the next week and also Hollow talk will
be recorded live during the event and
will be the program for the week of
March 15th so stay tuned for more
information on this
Steve Michael sent in a report this week
he's been working with code film for
making his laser pointer Holograms and
has had some success here is his email
which I will read to you
I just made a bright transmission with
Kodak so
253 film
4x5 equivalent in brightness to 8e75
which is agfa
it has an exposure rating of 5 ergs per
square centimeter for a density of one
and my exposure time was 3 seconds with
a beam intensity reading at the film
holder of 1.7 microwatts the laser
pointer was producing 2.45 milliwatts
undiverged
because of the anti-halation backing I
threw in Rapid fixer between the stop
bath and bleach and it worked
beautifully
cost of the film is about two dollars
and fifty cents per sheet
now I will try a reflection but I am
still trying to remove the
anti-hellation backing prior to exposure
kodak's suggestion didn't work which was
80 degree water with a two to five
percent acetic acid bath
Kodak says there's nothing special in
the fixer that removes the backing but I
know that's not true since I can see the
backing vanish rapidly using fixer I
have a good idea what component it is
and will experiment today on that aspect
and I will keep you posted on further
updates from Steve and his work
I had a group of students come in from
the New York area to learn about how to
make Holograms using a laser pointer and
after the workshop we sat down in the
studio recorded a few of their
Impressions and ideas on holography in
general it's always good to hear from
the upcoming generation and it will be
them that we will pass the torch onto in
the future here are a few audio clips
from our conversations and we have
Michael Brittany Samantha and Mom Joan
I'll be back right after you're finished
would you like to make your own
one-of-a-kind hologram and learn how you
can start making holograms on your own
at the same time you can do this and
much more by attending one of Frank's
greatest holography workshops from
beginner to Advanced Frank's got a
workshop that's just right for you from
single afternoon evening or weekend
introductory workshops to Wednesday
evening five-week complete courses and
don't forget his newest Workshop laser
pointer holography located just off the
Northeast Extension of the Pennsylvania
Turnpike and Interstate 78 the studio is
a quick non-stop drive from the New York
Philadelphia and Baltimore Washington DC
areas for more information call the
Studio's toll-free hotline at
1-800-458-3525 and begin your own
Journey with holography today that's
1-800-458-3525 for more information on
attending a Frankie greatest holography
Workshop today
thank you
okay this is Frankie Fighters welcome
back to whole talk I have a few guests
with me this week and we had a group of
people come in from just above New York
City and they came in to learn about
laser pointer holography and it's a
group of students ranging in age from
well Michael how old are you seven and
how old's the oldest in the group do you
know
11 11 years old
and you made a laser pointer hologram
today didn't you Michael
and what did you make the Hologram of a
cup of this bird on it a couple of the
bird on it yeah and uh it turned out
really nice didn't it yeah in fact I'm
going to take a picture of that hologram
before you go and we're going to put
that hologram up on the web page so that
people can see the Hologram that you
made and you made that using a laser
pointer right yep
um you've seen a lot of different
Holograms today over at the Museum right
yes what do you think would be
interesting thing for uh Holograms in
the future someday
and what about the pandas tell me what
you were telling me earlier about
Candace how you you could go to the zoo
pandas don't live that long if they get
two pandas and put two hologram pandas
so it depend the the real pandas won't
feel alone and they die only because
they're alone right and so they had a
whole Grand Panda to keep them company
they would live longer because they
think the Jewish set another panda in
there with them right and what did you
say about the skyscrapers the buildings
uh
can you remember what you were telling
me about that
no
I think you could um
the actual building of in a hologram so
people will know what it looks like when
it's built so in other words instead of
spending all the money to build a
building first and then have someone
come down the street and say you know
what I don't like that building we
wasted our money it would be a good idea
to make a hologram of the building first
and let the people see what the Hologram
looks like before they spent all the
time and all the money building it
that's what you meant right because I
know we explained that so did you have a
good time today and what are you going
to do with your hologram
I'm gonna hang it up you're gonna hang
it up that's a really nice hologram of
the cup Michael it was nice working with
you today
bye-bye
okay our second guest is Brittany and
Brittany how are you today
thank you hold on
folks in case you're wondering what that
was that was the weather
warning alarm so there's probably some
very bad weather moving into the area so
let me just turn it off Brittany I'm
very sorry how are you
thank you and what's your age
I'm 11 11 years old and you made a laser
pointer hologram today yes now don't you
find it amazing that you can make a
hologram with a laser pointer yes
especially how expensive lasers are
right yeah what was your hologram of I
think it was a ballerina wasn't it yeah
what material was the belt it was very
shiny do you know what it was made out
of was that solid gold no no not
ballerina I didn't think so
if that ballerina were solid gold you'd
have to probably have police bring you
to the house because someone would want
to take that from you real quick
you wrote down a few things and you had
a few ideas about what holography could
do in the future and I was wondering if
you could share that with us on the show
today okay
what are some of the things that you'd
like to see happen with holography what
are some of your ideas for the future
well instead of having a war with real
humans countries can decide who will win
raising uh hologram people and equipment
and earn points so no one can get hurt
so all the Hologram soldiers would go
out into the field
and fight each other without using real
people yes yeah what do you think about
using that with like the WWF the
worldwide Wrestling Federation you think
maybe we should have holographic
wrestlers too yeah yeah wouldn't that be
neat they could throw the wrestler out
into the audience onto your lap and
you'd never feel them
what else do you have on the sheet there
yeah you could watch other shows in your
own home
that would be neat or bellies
do you do ballon yes I thought so that's
why you brought the ballerina and you're
mentioning ballet uh ballet would be
very interesting to watch in your house
instead of watching it on TV a flat
picture to have that ballerina actually
right in the middle of the room at the
whole room do you have a few more there
you can have a flower blooming Holograms
which would last longer than real
flowers by floors
class driving test with Holograms so you
don't crash cars that's very good I bet
you I'll bet you Brittany that's
probably going to be one of the first
things that we see with holography
is one of the drive virtual reality
driving tests
hologram buttons can be on gravestones
in cemeteries so people can hear and see
the deceased that's another very good
idea you know I I feel like I should
have a hologram done of myself
so that someday my Generations will be
able to look back and see me and it's a
shame that so many famous people in the
world today are not being done as
Holograms do you know who is the only
United States president that has ever
done as a hologram do you know
did you give her that answer
who gave her the answer someone gave her
the answer okay well Brittany thank you
very much for being on the show yeah
okay
okay we've got another guest which is
Samantha Samantha how are you good and
uh uh 11 11 years old what grade are you
when you're 11 years old I can't
remember anymore six sixth grade that's
great
um you need a hologram today with a
laser pointer and what do you feel about
that do you think that's fascinating
yeah did you have a pretty good time
yeah now you worked in the dark room too
right you actually developed one of the
Holograms yeah and uh how did you find
out was that hard to do it was it easy
for you it was it was hard and easy but
it was fun what was the hard part
of developing the Hologram the missing
the chemicals mixing the chemicals and
what was the easy part
trying it trying it okay well you know
we need to know what some people think
are easy and what some people think we
are overall let me ask you this when you
thought that you were going to do a
hologram did you think it would be as
easy as what it turned out to be yeah
was it a lot easier than what you
thought it would be yes that's good to
hear because that's what we want we want
to make it easy for everybody now let me
ask you a question what do you think we
could do with holography in the future
you're gonna have school at home school
at home where a teacher would virtually
come into your living room
yeah not the bathroom there's certain
rooms at home you don't want the teacher
actually showing up and saying what's
the capital of France right
and any other ideas what you would like
to do uh
yeah what about what about having your
bedroom as a hologram
and then when your bedroom gets all
messed up and it's a wreck and your mom
or dad comes up and says clean this room
instead of cleaning it you just change
the hologram
that would be pretty neat wouldn't it
yeah do you think you may do hole guns
later on again sometime on your own
you think you would like to do that yeah
okay well Samantha I want to thank you
very much for coming in I know you guys
want to run it's getting late and as
many of you may have heard already that
was the second time the weather uh
warning alarm went off so there must be
something that
the area so we're going to let you get
on the road as soon as possible so thank
you for being on the show thank you okay
now you have something you wanted to add
to the show tell us what your name is hi
my name's John
and you'll have to tell us your last
name no don't don't tell because this is
the one that nobody wants to know
anybody's last names on and I you know I
know people like to have their privacy
what are some of the things that you
have as far as ideas why let me ask you
this why are your kids here making
Holograms
well they have a big interest in it and
when I went on to the internet and on
your website I thought this would be a
great way for them to learn about it
Hands-On was it a great way
absolutely sensation what do you think
of the Holograms especially the one that
Michael did what do you think of that
cup hologram that was absolutely
beautiful the quality
it looked like you actually could see
down into the cup and would you believe
that was possible to do with a little
7.99 laser pointer no I never would have
thought yeah it was a museum quality
yeah what are some of your ideas that
you have down there for holography in
the future
currently on computer they have age
progressions for missing
person by man
and transform the age progression image
into a hologram it would help people to
find a person
um years into the future because if you
have an actual moving image and use
digital recording to try to simulate
what you think the voice will silent
like also aged you'd have I think you'd
have a better way of finding people or
identifying them yep and with it being a
hologram that increases your chances as
well because you're just about in fact
you could probably take that holographic
image anywhere and have that projected
so people could see that yeah
um you know this holographic sound as
well that's been worked on for many
years as well yeah so you combine the
holographic sound of the voice you the
holographic image and uh do you have
something else
for insurance practices to remember the
contents of a home Inventory
um it's easier to catalog and if there's
a loss to or if it's sentimental reasons
yeah to look at something
maybe even Antiques and see what they
look like over time do you think that
would be more valuable as holography
rather than photography absolutely
because of this all the dimensions yeah
that's another very good application and
these are all very practical
applications as well that you're coming
up with here too and the only other
thing unless it's already done in
museums to feature famous people
doing the events that they go down in
history for and to have that on display
where kids can hit a button
see the person
it's never winning the Olympics or the
president making the state of the union
and wouldn't that be something yeah
yeah they're all very good ideas and
hopefully we'll get there someday and
what's really exciting about it is the
group of young people that you have here
with you today will probably be the
generation that does it and it may be
one of you yourself
that do it you never know you never know
you never know well thank all of you for
being on the show
thank you for having me yeah we're going
to log off here and find out what this
weather situation is and we'll be back
with more of whole talk in just a moment
so that's our show for this week folks
it was great working with the kids it
was actually uh very interestable to see
other people making Holograms using
laser pointers because I thought I was
living in a dream world there for a
little while thanks for tuning into the
show next week we should have a guest
and
I sent out a few emails to see who wants
to take the turn this week to come on so
when I get an email back we'll get one
of the guests on for next week don't
forget the laser diode updates I'm still
working on this where there's still a
lot of testing to be done so stay tuned
to the laser diode web pages and see the
latest work
and if you'd like to see the Holograms
first hand once again they will be
unveiled on Saturday evening March 6th
and at tinicum Falls New Jersey at the
central New Jersey Mensa event that may
be held there the 25th anniversary event
and I will be the keynote speaker that
evening and we'll be bringing Holograms
a little laser light show and we'll be
doing whole talk
actually right from the conference
itself so thank you very much for tuning
in and I'll see you next week